<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: India | Thien's Scribbles]]></title>
  <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/categories/india/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-05T11:19:23+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://thienscribbles.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Thien Truong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scribbles]]></title>
    <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/09/26/scribbles/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-26T14:43:31+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/09/26/scribbles</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>One week mark on India soil.</li>
<li>Apartment is on 9th floor &ndash; nice balcony with plants, has a TV with about 15 English movie/entertaining channels (including HBO), smells like sewer sometimes.</li>
<li>Apparently we have housekeeping 5 days/week.  The apartment caretaker refers to them as &ldquo;the boy&rdquo;.  They clean the house, wash the dishes, and empty the trash.  However, I&rsquo;ve been doing the dishes myself.  Hoping to keep it up.</li>
<li>Hindi phrase I can say:  Namaste, meraa naam Thien hai &ndash; Greetings, my name is Thien.</li>
<li>Have been going to Adam&rsquo;s office everyday this week.  Got lots of homework done.</li>
<li>Thoughtworks Pune provides free breakfasts, lunches, coffee, and snacks. Hot chai is served at 10 and 3.</li>
<li>Cooked dinner twice:  brinjai masala, sauteed flat green beans and long green beans.</li>
<li>Guava sellers tow about 50kg of guavas on their legendary rugged bicycles 25km each way from the orchards to Pune daily.  60Rs/kg.</li>
<li>Had two street food:  pani puri &ndash; thin crispy hollow bread ball filled with spicy tangy tamarind water, samosa: flaky fried pastry with savory fillings (spiced potatoes, onions, peas, lentils&hellip;).</li>
<li>Favorite items purchased:  guavas, custard apples, a pair of cleaning gloves.</li>
<li>Tip is about 10% at restaurants.</li>
<li>Prices for beer (and maybe alcohol in general) are printed on the can/bottle, no negotiation.</li>
<li>2.0km ride on a rickshaw costs about 25Rs to 30Rs, depending on traffic.  However, we have been quoted 50Rs, 60Rs, and even 100Rs.  People are relentless when it comes to overcharging us.</li>
<li>Adam found a pretty accurate rickshaw price sheet online.  When he showed it to the drivers, they say that such prices are only for locals.  Adam&rsquo;s reply? <strong>&ldquo;Bullshit!&rdquo;</strong> &ndash; of course accompanied by his usual booming laugh.</li>
<li>Most people speak very little English.</li>
<li>I have been messing up all the names of the people at work.  I shall prevail next week.</li>
<li>Gandhi&rsquo;s birthday is October 2nd, which is a national holiday.</li>
<li>Hindus are currently celebrating <a href="http://www.indiaonlinepages.com/festivals/navratri/">Navratri</a> &ndash;  the most celebrated Hindu festival devoted to Goddess Durga &ndash; September 25th to October 3rd this year.</li>
<li>Registration with the <a href="http://boi.gov.in/sites/default/files/RegForeigners-11.pdf">Foreigners Regional Registration Office (FRRO)</a> proved to be a nightmare as expected.  Adam had to make countless trips, most involved long period of waiting , and many of which he came back with nothing accomplished.</li>
<li>Daily operations and activities start much later than in the U.S.  People get to work at about 10:00.  Lunch is around 1:00-2:30.  Dinner is around 8:00-9:30.  Most restaurants do not serve dinner until 7:00.</li>
<li>The streets are extremely busy at night, especially where there are street food vendors.</li>
<li>From what I can see, the men run most of everything here.</li>
<li>Tuborg &ndash; a Denmark pilsner launched in India in 2009 &ndash; is 65Rs each and is pretty drinkable.</li>
<li>Adam&rsquo;s curiosity is about to get the better of him.  He will eat pizza to see if they are anything like the ones at home.</li>
<li>Too bad we missed Octoberfest this year.</li>
<li>Children do play outside a lot.  They are very loud too.</li>
<li>Traffic, pollution, and the heat are not bad.  Bearable!</li>
<li>Walking in sandals is not recommended.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arriving to Pune]]></title>
    <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/09/23/pune/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-23T16:20:09+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/09/23/pune</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The 92-mile drive from Mumbai to Pune took about four hours.  As the taxi driver expertly squeezed through the most unbelievably small spaces, the number of knots on my shoulder naturally increased.  Thankfully, most of the scenery were very peaceful and pleasant &ndash; lush mountains, long tunnels, grass fields, wild flowers, and the occasional monkeys on rail guards.</p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-MHwhHeS83UQ/VCUN56kGrmI/AAAAAAAADZA/xv3OwCJy5KM/w1472-h970-no/20140923DriveToPune.jpg">https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-MHwhHeS83UQ/VCUN56kGrmI/AAAAAAAADZA/xv3OwCJy5KM/w1472-h970-no/20140923DriveToPune.jpg</a>" width="700" height="462" title="Drive To Pune" ></p>

<p>Since Adam was off to Awayday in Hyderabad with his fellow <a href="http://www.thoughtworks.com/">Thoughtworkers</a> for the weekend, I arrived to an empty flat.  First order of business, sleep!  The room was so musky that I buried my nose into Misa&rsquo;s neck, trying to sniff out the perfume I sprayed on her before we left.</p>

<p>I woke up at five in the morning, famished. The three hours wait for the restaurants to be opened was unbearable.  Luckily, Kalyani Veg was right outside the complex.  Once there, I stuffed myself with Cheese Paper Masala Dosa and the heavenly Mango Pulp.</p>

<p>With a happy belly, I wandered for about 5 minutes each way from the apartment&rsquo;s main intersection.  The inevitalbe encounters with the beggar children were confronting and uncomfortable.  The second girl of about ten was carrying a toddler, maybe her sibling or a child her gang leader rented for her as a tool to beg with.  She has large burn marks on her face, her neck, and along her arms.  At first she slightly grabbed me, then outright started jabbing me with her finger.  As I firmly told her &ldquo;No&rdquo;, I knew this is only the first of many times I must walk away.  I do not know how to help her or the other millions beggars in this country.  I do not know if any one can either.</p>

<p>On a happier note, the first purchases from the locals on the way back to the apartment went pretty smoothly &ndash; custard apples and guavas.  Of course I failed to negotiate (thus the smooth part), but I came home with some of the tastiest fruits on this earth.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to India, Mr. Truong]]></title>
    <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/09/19/welcome-to-india/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-19T08:37:35+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/09/19/welcome-to-india</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I crossed all the phalanges I have and my wish came true.  My visa came back 10 days after I sent it in.  Even better, I applied for the 6 months entry visa and they granted my stay until Adam&rsquo;s visa expires &ndash; August 28, 2015.  However, each of my stay cannot exceed 180 days, which will not be a problem since I&rsquo;ll come home for Christmas.</p>

<p>Two days later, after some speedy packing, house cleaning, and last minute errand running, I said goodbye to home and headed to Mumbai.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Mr. Truong&rdquo; &ndash; the sign read when the hotel&rsquo;s cab driver greeted me at Chhatrapati Shivaji International Airport (BOM) last night.  Well, Mr. Truong was all chatty until &ldquo;he&rdquo; realized that the driver did not talk much at all.  He did not smile, mostly just pointed me to the direction needed.  I was not helping the situation when I absolutely forgot to tip him.</p>

<p>Tipping is such a tricky business when traveling to a new country.  When should I tip?  How much is appropriate?  I should have read up on it before I left, but oh well.  Plenty of chances to practice now that I&rsquo;m gonna be here for the next 6 months or so.</p>

<p>The drive from BOM to the hotel was short, about 15 mintues.  The streets were still very active at 9:30 p.m.  Men gathered into countless small groups at all the tiny shops and shags.  Many wandered nonchalantly on the streets.  From what I&rsquo;ve seen, Mumbai seems old and run down &ndash; many slums.  The streets are narrow and somewhat dark.  Most of the lights were from street vendors.</p>

<p>The quiet driver dropped me off at Hotel Kohinoor Continental.  Dinner buffet and breakfast were complimentary.  Since I just had &ldquo;breakfast&rdquo; on the plane, I settled for some water over dinner.  My room was on the 5th floor over looking the streets below.  I stayed up until four in the morning doing homework just to find out that I could not upload my assignement due to the hotel&rsquo;s excruciatingly slow Internet.  After a shower with some very powerful scented shampoo and bar soap, I force myself to nap for a few hours so that I can wake up in time for breakfast not feeling like a cranky zombie.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things Are in Motion]]></title>
    <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/09/10/things-are-in-motion/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-10T11:31:50+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/09/10/things-are-in-motion</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After what seemed to be forever, Adam finally got his visa last week and now is on his twenty-hours flight to Mumbai.  His company will send a person with a sign that says &ldquo;Mr. Russell&rdquo; at the airport and take him to his apartment in Pune.  I was relieved to know that he will not have to try to find a cab at 4 in the morning.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello Again]]></title>
    <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/08/23/hello-again/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-23T01:03:20+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/08/23/hello-again</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been too long since I last had a blog. Typing these first few lines seems rather silly and unfamiliar.</p>

<p>This summer has been a mixture of suspense, rush, and leisure.</p>

<p>Adam is still waiting patiently for his <a href="http://www.in.ckgs.us/visa/type-of-visa/employment-visa.shtml">employment visa</a> from the Indian Consulate in Houston. Since May 21, 2014, <a href="http://www.in.ckgs.us/index.shtml">Cox &amp; Kings Global Service</a> (CKGS) is the only authorized Service Provider for the Embassy of India and its Consulates across the USA for Indian Visa. The process has been more than painful.  All the paper works must first go through CKGS before they send it to the Indian Consulate.  Forget competency, forget sanity, forget reason.  Don&rsquo;t be surprise if they still ask for a tax form (which was not listed in the required documents) after you already re-submitted the dang form three times previously.  Seven weeks have passed since Adam first submitted the lengthy paper works.  Still nothing.  Imagine of having to deal directly with pure bureaucrats once on Indian soil!  Should I start &ldquo;praying&rdquo; for our survival?</p>

<p>As much as I am excited to experience India, I am starting to get wary about this trip.  I cannot even apply for my <a href="http://www.in.ckgs.us/visa/type-of-visa/entry-visa.shtml">entry visa</a> until Adam get his.  Who knows how much longer they will drag it out since I was not born here (naturalized citizen takes longer to be processed than American-born).  There is a chance that Adam will be finished with his 6-month assignment and I am still visa-less.  Hah!</p>

<p>Oh well, at least I am still alive and well for another day.  Just a weekend with coconut chicken waffle and yummy beer, and all the blues will be away.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
