<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Traveling Tips | Scribbles]]></title>
  <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/categories/traveling-tips/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-31T11:31:46+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://thienscribbles.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Thien Truong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nepal Travel Tips]]></title>
    <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2015/03/30/travel-tips-for-visiting-nepal/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-30T00:32:10+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2015/03/30/travel-tips-for-visiting-nepal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Prior to your trip:</p>

<ul>
<li>If you leave from India, book your flights 30-59 days in advance; this is when Indian airlines are most likely to offer the best deal.</li>
<li>  Fill out the <a href="http://online.nepalimmigration.gov.np/tourist-visa">online visa application</a>. The interface used for this is very crappy, so doing it while having a buzz would be a good idea. The site times out a lot; and there are restrictions on the number of characters that can be entered for each field (of course it does not give you these warnings until after you submit).  As for the Nepal hotel address field, enter some gibberish if you cannot find your ward number, district, or municipality.  For the passport picture, take one with your phone on a light background, crop it, then upload (no need to be perfect with picture quality or size).  Upon successfully submitting, print out the confirmation page.</li>
<li>Make a copy of your passport and your latest visa page.</li>
<li>Bring a pen to fill out disembarkation form (no pen will be provided at the airport).</li>
</ul>


<p><figure class='caption-wrapper' style='width:px;'><img class='caption center' src='https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-gDR8aZHyfbk/VRopxbmguZI/AAAAAAAAFyw/rGUQ6HNHzEc/w1352-h934-no/Screen%2BShot%2B2015-03-31%2Bat%2B10.16.38%2BAM.png">https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-gDR8aZHyfbk/VRopxbmguZI/AAAAAAAAFyw/rGUQ6HNHzEc/w1352-h934-no/Screen%2BShot%2B2015-03-31%2Bat%2B10.16.38%2BAM.png</a>&#8217; width=&#8221; height=&#8221; title=&#8217;Online visa application confirmation page&#8217;><figcaption class='caption-text'>Online visa application confirmation page</figcaption></figure></p>

<p>At Tribhuvan International airport:</p>

<ul>
<li>After getting off the plane, fill out the disembarkation form (which can be found right before reaching immigration), get in line to pay for visa fee (exact change is best), then you will be given a receipt and directed to the officer that will stamp the visa in your passport.</li>
<li>The foreign exchange rate at the airport is not bad.  Note that the exchange rate changes by the hour, so when you see a good rate, exchange as much as you can.  When we went, we got about 97 NPR for each 1 USD.</li>
<li>There are places to buy sim cards at the airport.</li>
</ul>


<p>Miscellaneous:</p>

<ul>
<li>There are power cuts 70% of the time.  If your hotel does not have a generator, that means no Internet, no hot shower, no charging batteries.</li>
<li>Cold showers are common.</li>
<li>Nightly temperatures in February are low (about 37 – 42 degree Fahrenheit); and most hotels do not have heaters.</li>
<li>Kathmandu is extremely dusty.  Use a mask or risk getting bronchitis (which Adam got – he coughed like a nut for a whole month after).</li>
<li>Lots of restaurants/hotels take credit card, but they will charge an additional 4%.</li>
<li>Hotels are not noise proof, bring earplugs.</li>
<li>“Namaste” is the key to all the smiles.  I literally go around and say “Namaste” to everybody.  When I got tired, Adam took over.  Our system worked out quite well.</li>
<li>Thamel (where most tourists stay in Kathmandu) is the heaven for souvenirs.  Don’t wait to buy in less touristy spots because the amount and variety are also likely to decrease.</li>
<li>No exciting food in Nepal. We tipped 10% at restaurants if there were no service charge.</li>
<li>In the winter, sourvenir shops close down at about 8:00. The streets tend to get very eerie because there are very few streetlights.</li>
<li>No need to visit all the Dubar Squares in Kathmandu Valley since they are very similar.   Patan Dubar Square and Bhaktapur Dubar Square are not worth it at all (in my opinion).</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tough Love in Nepal]]></title>
    <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2015/03/29/tough-love-in-nepal/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-29T16:08:25+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2015/03/29/tough-love-in-nepal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So many times I want to write about our trip to Nepal last February but the words keep finding way to hide.  I lost motivation mainly because it was not as a successful trip as I had hoped, especially since I spent so much time planning for it.  So here I am, yanking out my hair writing this, hoping that if I can get all the frustrating parts out of the way, the rest would be easier.</p>

<p>To keep the trip inexpensive and allow for lots of time to relax, I opted to stay in the Kathmandu Valley area, which comprises of three ancient cities: Kathmandu, Patan and Bhaktapur.  Our itinerary for the week was simple:</p>

<ul>
<li>Day 1, 2, 3: Arrive in Thamel. Visit Kathmandu Dubar Square, Swayambhunath, Boudhanath and Patan Dubar Square.</li>
<li>Day 4: Trek to Nagarkot</li>
<li>Day 5: Trek to Dhulikhel</li>
<li>Day 6, 7: Wind down in Bhaktapur.</li>
<li>Day 8: Go home.</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="http://welcomenepal.com/promotional/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Entry-Fees-to-Heritage-Sites.pdf">Entrance fees</a> for most attractions are ridiculously higher for foreigners except for SAARC nationals; and the same goes for <a href="http://www.yetiairlines.com/yeti-fares.html">airplane tickets</a> to any parts of Nepal. Pokhara, a destination 200km away, was very tempting but I couldn’t justify spending $120 each way on airfare for each person, especially when the flight is only 25-minute long.  From what Adam gathered, Nepal was once an integral part of what was called the &ldquo;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hippie_trail">Hippie Trail</a>&rdquo; – a journey travelled from Europe overland to southern Asia with the goal to spend as little money as possible.  Since these “hippie visitors” do not contribute much to Nepal&rsquo;s heavily tourism dependent economy, its government decides to levy high fees accross all foreigner related services.</p>

<p>The discrimination in price was already nipping at me but I held it in, until we arrived to Bhaktapur. In Kathmandu and Patan, you enter the cities and then only buy tickets if you want to see a particular sight. In Bhaktapur, tickets are required the second you step foot inside the city limit since the whole thing is considered a heritage site (which I didn&rsquo;t know). Tickets are at a hefty $15 per person; but you still have to pay extra if you want to visit the museums and such. I would not have been so angry if only the Dubar Square here could even compare to the one in Kathmandu. For twice the price, I expected a whole lot more.  What a scam!!! Thankfully we found the perfect souvenir here: an exquisite singing bowl.  I think it helped calming down my rage and disappointment; but this city definitely made my black list.</p>

<p>So except for Bhaktapur and Boudhanath and Patan Dubar Square, everything else was great.  We had the best pizza ever at Fire and Ice, and drank so many sweet lassi.  We experienced our first hookah and loved it.  We trekked until my thighs were chafed and my toenails turned purple (my hiking shoes does not like the fact that my index toes are a lot longer than my big toes - CREEPY!).  All in all, we were glad we made the trip.  Mistakes made and learned; and we are one country richer than before we left.</p>

<p><figure class='caption-wrapper' style='width:px;'><img class='caption center' src='https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-xu-9yHLMuZA/VRgBG2WkBqI/AAAAAAAAFx4/R-hHyYnFFlI/w1292-h934-no/Screen%2BShot%2B2015-03-29%2Bat%2B7.09.06%2BPM.png">https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-xu-9yHLMuZA/VRgBG2WkBqI/AAAAAAAAFx4/R-hHyYnFFlI/w1292-h934-no/Screen%2BShot%2B2015-03-29%2Bat%2B7.09.06%2BPM.png</a>&#8217; width=&#8221; height=&#8221; title=&#8217;Kathmandu, Nepal&#8217;><figcaption class='caption-text'>Kathmandu, Nepal</figcaption></figure></p>

<p><figure class='caption-wrapper' style='width:px;'><img class='caption center' src='https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-9JbBfvEVMuo/VRgD4BzkJ8I/AAAAAAAAFyU/z_bcihUAMc4/w1764-h934-no/Screen%2BShot%2B2015-03-29%2Bat%2B7.20.22%2BPM.png">https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-9JbBfvEVMuo/VRgD4BzkJ8I/AAAAAAAAFyU/z_bcihUAMc4/w1764-h934-no/Screen%2BShot%2B2015-03-29%2Bat%2B7.20.22%2BPM.png</a>&#8217; width=&#8221; height=&#8221; title=&#8217;Our journey: Thamel - Nagarkot - Dhulikhel - Bhaktapur&#8217;><figcaption class='caption-text'>Our journey: Thamel - Nagarkot - Dhulikhel - Bhaktapur</figcaption></figure></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
