<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Indian Bank Account | Scribbles]]></title>
  <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/categories/indian-bank-account/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-31T11:31:46+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://thienscribbles.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Thien Truong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pleasant Little Surprises]]></title>
    <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/10/01/pleasant-little-surprises/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-01T15:58:34+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/10/01/pleasant-little-surprises</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last work day before the long holiday weekend and I find myself too distracted for homework.  While I leisurely sip on the freshly pressed pineapple juice, Adam is working as diligently as ever.  Two tables away and amongst all the buzzy Thoughtworkers, his frequent booming laughs resonate the whole room.  They are strangely soothing, especially for a rainy day like today.</p>

<p>So we officially have a guava man.  He parks in front of our complex every morning from Monday through Saturday.  We were disappointed not seeing him last Sunday, but glad that he has a day off.  His guavas are always fresh and happy. Some days he even has pomegranates.  He (and seemingly other fruit sellers - on bikes or in little shops) does not negotiate.  That makes everything so much easier.  Now when he sees us approaching, he would raise his index finger signaling if we would like to buy one kilogram.  Of course I grin and nod.  He then would pick one guava, look at me to see if I approve, then put it in a bag.  After about 5 guavas and 60 Rupees later, I walk away with my yummies, extremely happy.</p>

<p>There have been a few other events this week that got me to relax my armor a little. On the way home from work last night, we did not have to haggle for rickshaw fare for the first time.  I was shocked when the driver just pointed to the meter counter.  If Adam were not so busy rushing me inside the rickshaw, I would have kicked him to see if we were dreaming.  Then this morning after a wild goose chase to find Citibank office, a nice man gave us a partial lift with &ldquo;real&rdquo; directions to the bank.  Apparently Google maps in this part of the world are not as reliable yet.  And of course differentiating between an ATM and a &ldquo;real&rdquo; branch could be a bit tricky.</p>

<p>In order to make any major financial transactions (opening bank account, large sales or purchases of assets&hellip;) in India, one must first <a href="https://tin.tin.nsdl.com/pan/">apply</a> for a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Permanent_account_number">Permanent Account Number (PAN)</a> - an identifier of Indian income tax payers.  According to the bank assistance, the PAN card - which will bear the face-photo of the holder, date of birth, date of issue and a hologram sticker as security feature - will come in the mail in about two weeks.  However when opening an account, Citibank will accept the receipt of the application.  Once the card comes, they will add it to the profile.  Other documents include passport, visa, <a href="http://boi.gov.in/content/registration-requirements-foreign-national">FRRO paper works</a>, another form of ID such as driver license, and a letter from HR from the company employed.</p>

<p>Adam&rsquo;s company has initiated the application for his PAN&hellip; Hopefully it will come soon so he can start getting direct deposit instead. Mama has wired $500 to us through Western Union with the fee of $11.  Eleven dollars mean 677 Rupees of heavenly street food - a feast I rather not have to give to Western Union.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
