<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Scribbles | Scribbles]]></title>
  <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/categories/scribbles/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-29T22:03:28+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://thienscribbles.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Thien Truong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scribbles]]></title>
    <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2015/01/31/scribbles/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-31T00:10:37+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2015/01/31/scribbles</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>My sister will turn 21 in 14 days.</li>
<li>Going to Nepal tomorrow for a week.  Momos, monkeys, and trekking - here we come!</li>
<li>Made vegetable meals 3 times this week.</li>
<li>Have been productive in programming.</li>
<li>Had my first 5-star hotel experience in Bangalore.  Thank you Marriott for the free nights and the executive suite.</li>
<li>Crawfish will be plentiful and cheap this year - cannot wait for a crawfish boil.</li>
<li>Less than one month until the Vietnamese New Year.  This will be the 15th year I won&rsquo;t be home celebrating with families.  Nostalgic!</li>
<li>Finally found out where my favorite Indian cookies are sold - right across the street from the apartment. I have been hunting for them for 3 months.  Boom!</li>
<li>Not everybody in the world use toilet papers.  Many use water and left hands instead.  Not sure what to think about that (I miss my Charmin Ultra Strong).</li>
<li>Raspberry black current smoothie at Cafe Colombia is addictive.</li>
<li>Learned a few Nepali words.</li>
<li>Bunster got some creepy blisters playing soccer with his coworkers.  Last game he scored a goal with his head.  And sprained his hand a little too.</li>
<li>Thien&rsquo;s camera is a champion.  The thing survives a 3 feet fall directly onto the rocks in Hampi.</li>
<li>Favorite new band:  <a href="http://youtu.be/iVRK1xl4gbA">KUAN</a></li>
<li>Will be going to Turkey for a month in mid Feb.</li>
<li>Heard some great news from my mom.  So proud of her and so happy for her.</li>
<li>Cannot sleep well without Misa&hellip; Murrr.</li>
<li>The music didn&rsquo;t play until 10 at night on Republic day.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scribbles]]></title>
    <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/12/05/scribbles/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-05T10:26:34+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/12/05/scribbles</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>2.5 months in India.</li>
<li>Had a blast attending an Indian wedding in Solapur and hanging out with friends/co-workers in scenic Hampi last weekend.</li>
<li>The weather has been extremely pleasant; I cannot say I miss the winter in the U.S.</li>
<li>Adam got a fever last night. Poor the fur ball, too much play and not enough sleep.</li>
<li>The planning for Nepal trip in Feb is 95% done.  Tickets booked, hotels/guest houses reserved.  Only thing left is to confirm guide and porter for trekking trip.</li>
<li>Two more weeks until we fly home for the break.  Way behind on Christmas shopping.</li>
<li>Breakfast and lunch are much more comforting now that the food vendors are changed in the cafeteria.  I kept finding hairs in my food with the old ones.  Haizz&hellip; and sometimes I don&rsquo;t think they were hairs from the head.</li>
<li>Favorite Indian starter:  chicken lollipop. Succulent flavorful heaven.</li>
<li>I know I&rsquo;m spoiled when I cannot do business in a swat toilet.  I even sang to coax myself but it didn&rsquo;t work.  Bahhh.</li>
<li>Always bring toilet paper when traveling in India.</li>
<li>I told Adam that it would be cloudy all the time we were in Solapur and Hampi. The result?  He got some serious sunburn.  The lesson? Don&rsquo;t trust Thien to look up the weather.</li>
<li>Cutest Indian saying: &ldquo;click&rdquo;.  They use the word &ldquo;click&rdquo; instead of &ldquo;take picture&rdquo;.  Such as:  &ldquo;Will you click me?&rdquo;, &ldquo;Nice clickworks!&rdquo;</li>
<li>Big banana:  5 rupees each.  Tiny banana:  5 rupees each.  What??? How could that be when they taste equally good? Oh well, bigger is better.</li>
<li>I haven&rsquo;t seen my guava man for almost a week.  I&rsquo;m worried and sad.  But that did not stop me from having an affair with another guava man who sells red-flesh guavas.  I mean, even Bunster does not blame me.</li>
<li>I must confess my shame to maah spoony sister:  I eat McDonald!!!! And I like it.  The McSpicy is so good here.</li>
<li>I think I&rsquo;m starting to like India.</li>
</ul>


<p><figure class='caption-wrapper' style='width:px;'><img class='caption center' src='https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-NibyAjDEH9o/VIFL-GeRnOI/AAAAAAAAE74/LGWkz2wmvos/w1434-h1062-no/20141205Scribbles.jpg">https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-NibyAjDEH9o/VIFL-GeRnOI/AAAAAAAAE74/LGWkz2wmvos/w1434-h1062-no/20141205Scribbles.jpg</a>&#8217; width=&#8221; height=&#8221; title=&#8217;India has the most delicious bananas.  This is our favorite place to get them yummies (2 blocks away from our apartment).&#8217;><figcaption class='caption-text'>India has the most delicious bananas.  This is our favorite place to get them yummies (2 blocks away from our apartment).</figcaption></figure></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scribbles]]></title>
    <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/10/17/scribbles/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-17T12:14:48+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/10/17/scribbles</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Four weeks mark in India.</li>
<li>Adam got his first food poisoning 2 weeks ago.  Two whole days of hell and a week of running away from food.  Now he is scarred of the words &ldquo;pani puri&rdquo; or &ldquo;sizzlers&rdquo;.  I still like pani puri too much.</li>
<li>Mama is spoiling us by sending a care package.  Aw&hellip; I will be able to make chicken noodle in case of emergency.  She is also sending chopsticks.</li>
<li>The rickshaw drivers in front of the complex are ganging up on us.  There is a man that seems to be the boss of this particular group.  He was reasonable, but not always present.  He knows that our price is 30 rupees and tells one of the driver to take us.  Unless the head-man is there, they all demand 40 rupees for the ride to work.  We had to give in this morning.  Locals only pay 22-25 rupees.</li>
<li>We will try to rent a motorbike/moped this weekend to stop this rickshaw madness.</li>
<li>Vegetables are extremely cheap over here, while seafood and meat are quite expensive.</li>
<li>Made chicken phở last week.  The chicken had good texture and was very flavorful.  Neither Huy Fong Sriracha nor sawtooth corriander were available.</li>
<li>Indians do not eat much noodles of any kind.  We got a package of rice noodle made from Thailand for 245 rupees (4 dollars).  In the US, they only cost $1.50 each.</li>
<li>Not much appetite for Indian food these days.  Everything start to taste the same or very similar.  Too much sauce, too much spices, and too much oil.</li>
<li>I have been dreaming of my dad quite a lot.  Miss him terribly.  Sometimes during my dreams, I suddenly remember that he was dead, so I made him die to match reality.</li>
<li>I learned how to play StarCraft II.  My non-existent sense of direction is very frustrating.  Adam shows me where to build my assets, then of course I build them somewhere else completely different.  Then I could not find them when I need them later either.  Pathetic!</li>
<li>We both seem to lose some weight.</li>
<li>My uncle called me from Vietnam two weeks ago.  We had a long nice chat.</li>
<li>I am planning a three weeks trip to Vietnam with 3 days stop-over in Bangkok at the end of Adam&rsquo;s assignment.  Hope everything will go as planned. Getting visas to Vietnam will be the trickiest part.</li>
<li>I miss sleepovers with my sister, Rebecca.  We usually watch Big Bang Theory and eat lots of snacks.  Salt and vinegar chips and sea salt caramel gelato are our favorites.  She has a special way of rolling down the bag so that I don&rsquo;t have to reach deep to grab the chips.  We do other happy things too which I will not mention until next Valentine day :)</li>
<li>Food I will devour when coming back to the States:  avocado eggrolls, California burger, and white chocolate macadamia nut pizookie from BJ&rsquo;s; Korean BBQ from Omi; mac and cheese from Slow Bone; Adam&rsquo;s delicious steak and grilled baby bell peppers with mint and feta.</li>
<li>Our neighbors from upstairs systematically make loud and annoying thud thud thud sounds through our ceiling at 8 every single morning.  I already ruled out sex, so chopping meat maybe?</li>
<li>My mom is going on a week long vacation tomorrow.  Wish I could be with her.</li>
<li>Tickets back to the U.S. for Christmas are booked.  Cannot wait for some family and friend time, and of course homemade eggnog.</li>
<li>The Indian people I have meet are mostly reserved. But a few of them are very friendly.  Four people give me big smiles when we cross path everyday:  a gate guard at the apartment complex, a gate guard and two house keeping ladies at work.  Guava man and dabeli guy also smile back when I wave at them.</li>
<li>I feel safe here, at least in Pune.  Nobody tries to rob, rape, kidnap, or murder me (yet).  But of course I will always be careful.  If foreigners/tourists exercise reasonable precaution, there is not much to worry about.</li>
<li>Adam&rsquo;s favorite street food is dabeli - a spicy snack made by mixing boiled potatoes with a dabeli masala, and putting the mixture between pav (burger bun) and served with chutneys made from tamarind, date, garlic, red chilies&hellip; and garnished with pomegranate and roasted peanuts.  The dabeli is then toasted on a hot metal plate.</li>
</ul>


<p><figure class='caption-wrapper' style='width:px;'><img class='caption center' src='https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-WpcKp7l6LVc/VEDvXwwRXyI/AAAAAAAADl4/4vz4p7WkuEM/w1330-h998-no/20141017Scribbles.jpg">https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-WpcKp7l6LVc/VEDvXwwRXyI/AAAAAAAADl4/4vz4p7WkuEM/w1330-h998-no/20141017Scribbles.jpg</a>&#8217; width=&#8221; height=&#8221; title=&#8217;Adam is getting some dabelies from our favorite stall, right accoss from our apartment complex&#8217;><figcaption class='caption-text'>Adam is getting some dabelies from our favorite stall, right accoss from our apartment complex</figcaption></figure></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scribbles]]></title>
    <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/09/26/scribbles/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-26T14:43:31+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/09/26/scribbles</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>One week mark on India soil.</li>
<li>Apartment is on 9th floor - nice balcony with plants, has a TV with about 15 English movie/entertaining channels (including HBO), smells like sewer sometimes.</li>
<li>Apparently we have housekeeping 5 days/week.  The apartment caretaker refers to them as &ldquo;the boy&rdquo;.  They clean the house, wash the dishes, and empty the trash.  However, I&rsquo;ve been doing the dishes myself.  Hoping to keep it up.</li>
<li>Hindi phrase I can say:  Namaste, meraa naam Thien hai - Greetings, my name is Thien.</li>
<li>Have been going to Adam&rsquo;s office everyday this week.  Got lots of homework done.</li>
<li>Thoughtworks Pune provides free breakfasts, lunches, coffee, and snacks. Hot chai is served at 10 and 3.</li>
<li>Cooked dinner twice:  brinjai masala, sauteed flat green beans and long green beans.</li>
<li>Guava sellers tow about 50kg of guavas on their legendary rugged bicycles 25km each way from the orchards to Pune daily.  60Rs/kg.</li>
<li>Had two street food:  pani puri - thin crispy hollow bread ball filled with spicy tangy tamarind water, samosa: flaky fried pastry with savory fillings (spiced potatoes, onions, peas, lentils&hellip;).</li>
<li>Favorite items purchased:  guavas, custard apples, a pair of cleaning gloves.</li>
<li>Tip is about 10% at restaurants.</li>
<li>Prices for beer (and maybe alcohol in general) are printed on the can/bottle, no negotiation.</li>
<li>2.0km ride on a rickshaw costs about 25Rs to 30Rs, depending on traffic.  However, we have been quoted 50Rs, 60Rs, and even 100Rs.  People are relentless when it comes to overcharging us.</li>
<li>Adam found a pretty accurate rickshaw price sheet online.  When he showed it to the drivers, they say that such prices are only for locals.  Adam&rsquo;s reply? <strong>&ldquo;Bullshit!&rdquo;</strong> - of course accompanied by his usual booming laugh.</li>
<li>Most people speak very little English.</li>
<li>I have been messing up all the names of the people at work.  I shall prevail next week.</li>
<li>Gandhi&rsquo;s birthday is October 2nd, which is a national holiday.</li>
<li>Hindus are currently celebrating <a href="http://www.indiaonlinepages.com/festivals/navratri/">Navratri</a> -  the most celebrated Hindu festival devoted to Goddess Durga - September 25th to October 3rd this year.</li>
<li>Registration with the <a href="http://boi.gov.in/sites/default/files/RegForeigners-11.pdf">Foreigners Regional Registration Office (FRRO)</a> proved to be a nightmare as expected.  Adam had to make countless trips, most involved long period of waiting , and many of which he came back with nothing accomplished.</li>
<li>Daily operations and activities start much later than in the U.S.  People get to work at about 10:00.  Lunch is around 1:00-2:30.  Dinner is around 8:00-9:30.  Most restaurants do not serve dinner until 7:00.</li>
<li>The streets are extremely busy at night, especially where there are street food vendors.</li>
<li>From what I can see, the men run most of everything here.</li>
<li>Tuborg - a Denmark pilsner launched in India in 2009 - is 65Rs each and is pretty drinkable.</li>
<li>Adam&rsquo;s curiosity is about to get the better of him.  He will eat pizza to see if they are anything like the ones at home.</li>
<li>Too bad we missed Octoberfest this year.</li>
<li>Children do play outside a lot.  They are very loud too.</li>
<li>Traffic, pollution, and the heat are not bad.  Bearable!</li>
<li>Walking in sandals is not recommended.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
