<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Scribbles | Thien's Scribbles]]></title>
  <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/categories/scribbles/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-05T11:19:23+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://thienscribbles.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Thien Truong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scribbles]]></title>
    <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/09/26/scribbles/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-26T14:43:31+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/09/26/scribbles</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>One week mark on India soil.</li>
<li>Apartment is on 9th floor &ndash; nice balcony with plants, has a TV with about 15 English movie/entertaining channels (including HBO), smells like sewer sometimes.</li>
<li>Apparently we have housekeeping 5 days/week.  The apartment caretaker refers to them as &ldquo;the boy&rdquo;.  They clean the house, wash the dishes, and empty the trash.  However, I&rsquo;ve been doing the dishes myself.  Hoping to keep it up.</li>
<li>Hindi phrase I can say:  Namaste, meraa naam Thien hai &ndash; Greetings, my name is Thien.</li>
<li>Have been going to Adam&rsquo;s office everyday this week.  Got lots of homework done.</li>
<li>Thoughtworks Pune provides free breakfasts, lunches, coffee, and snacks. Hot chai is served at 10 and 3.</li>
<li>Cooked dinner twice:  brinjai masala, sauteed flat green beans and long green beans.</li>
<li>Guava sellers tow about 50kg of guavas on their legendary rugged bicycles 25km each way from the orchards to Pune daily.  60Rs/kg.</li>
<li>Had two street food:  pani puri &ndash; thin crispy hollow bread ball filled with spicy tangy tamarind water, samosa: flaky fried pastry with savory fillings (spiced potatoes, onions, peas, lentils&hellip;).</li>
<li>Favorite items purchased:  guavas, custard apples, a pair of cleaning gloves.</li>
<li>Tip is about 10% at restaurants.</li>
<li>Prices for beer (and maybe alcohol in general) are printed on the can/bottle, no negotiation.</li>
<li>2.0km ride on a rickshaw costs about 25Rs to 30Rs, depending on traffic.  However, we have been quoted 50Rs, 60Rs, and even 100Rs.  People are relentless when it comes to overcharging us.</li>
<li>Adam found a pretty accurate rickshaw price sheet online.  When he showed it to the drivers, they say that such prices are only for locals.  Adam&rsquo;s reply? <strong>&ldquo;Bullshit!&rdquo;</strong> &ndash; of course accompanied by his usual booming laugh.</li>
<li>Most people speak very little English.</li>
<li>I have been messing up all the names of the people at work.  I shall prevail next week.</li>
<li>Gandhi&rsquo;s birthday is October 2nd, which is a national holiday.</li>
<li>Hindus are currently celebrating <a href="http://www.indiaonlinepages.com/festivals/navratri/">Navratri</a> &ndash;  the most celebrated Hindu festival devoted to Goddess Durga &ndash; September 25th to October 3rd this year.</li>
<li>Registration with the <a href="http://boi.gov.in/sites/default/files/RegForeigners-11.pdf">Foreigners Regional Registration Office (FRRO)</a> proved to be a nightmare as expected.  Adam had to make countless trips, most involved long period of waiting , and many of which he came back with nothing accomplished.</li>
<li>Daily operations and activities start much later than in the U.S.  People get to work at about 10:00.  Lunch is around 1:00-2:30.  Dinner is around 8:00-9:30.  Most restaurants do not serve dinner until 7:00.</li>
<li>The streets are extremely busy at night, especially where there are street food vendors.</li>
<li>From what I can see, the men run most of everything here.</li>
<li>Tuborg &ndash; a Denmark pilsner launched in India in 2009 &ndash; is 65Rs each and is pretty drinkable.</li>
<li>Adam&rsquo;s curiosity is about to get the better of him.  He will eat pizza to see if they are anything like the ones at home.</li>
<li>Too bad we missed Octoberfest this year.</li>
<li>Children do play outside a lot.  They are very loud too.</li>
<li>Traffic, pollution, and the heat are not bad.  Bearable!</li>
<li>Walking in sandals is not recommended.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
