<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Mumbai | Scribbles]]></title>
  <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/categories/mumbai/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-26T13:30:00+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://thienscribbles.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Thien Truong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to India, Mr. Truong]]></title>
    <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/09/19/welcome-to-india/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-19T08:37:35+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/09/19/welcome-to-india</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I crossed all the phalanges I have and my wish came true.  My visa came back 10 days after I sent it in.  Even better, I applied for the 6 months entry visa and they granted my stay until Adam&rsquo;s visa expires - August 28, 2015.  However, each of my stay cannot exceed 180 days, which will not be a problem since I&rsquo;ll come home for Christmas.</p>

<p>Two days later, after some speedy packing, house cleaning, and last minute errand running, I said goodbye to home and headed to Mumbai.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Mr. Truong&rdquo; - the sign read when the hotel&rsquo;s cab driver greeted me at Chhatrapati Shivaji International Airport (BOM) last night.  Well, Mr. Truong was all chatty until &ldquo;he&rdquo; realized that the driver did not talk much at all.  He did not smile, mostly just pointed me to the direction needed.  I was not helping the situation when I absolutely forgot to tip him.</p>

<p>Tipping is such a tricky business when traveling to a new country.  When should I tip?  How much is appropriate?  I should have read up on it before I left, but oh well.  Plenty of chances to practice now that I&rsquo;m gonna be here for the next 6 months or so.</p>

<p>The drive from BOM to the hotel was short, about 15 mintues.  The streets were still very active at 9:30 p.m.  Men gathered into countless small groups at all the tiny shops and shags.  Many wandered nonchalantly on the streets.  From what I&rsquo;ve seen, Mumbai seems old and run down - many slums.  The streets are narrow and somewhat dark.  Most of the lights were from street vendors.</p>

<p>The quiet driver dropped me off at Hotel Kohinoor Continental.  Dinner buffet and breakfast were complimentary.  Since I just had &ldquo;breakfast&rdquo; on the plane, I settled for some water over dinner.  My room was on the 5th floor over looking the streets below.  I stayed up until four in the morning doing homework just to find out that I could not upload my assignement due to the hotel&rsquo;s excruciatingly slow Internet.  After a shower with some very powerful scented shampoo and bar soap, I force myself to nap for a few hours so that I can wake up in time for breakfast not feeling like a cranky zombie.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
