<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Personal | Scribbles]]></title>
  <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-22T15:10:47+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://thienscribbles.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Thien Truong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Another Day]]></title>
    <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/10/22/another-day/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-22T10:58:25+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/10/22/another-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Time flies.  Too fast for my own good.</p>

<p>India has been a treat, but it has also been a burden.  Some days I wake up feeling invincible, like nothing could stop me from having all the fun in the world.  I dress up pretty, parade happily on the streets, smile and wave at familiar faces (sometimes I wave at strangers by mistakes too), and chip chirp until Adam&rsquo;s ears fall off.  Some days I just want to claw somebody&rsquo;s face out thinking of mundane things such as will we have dial up speed for the Internet, will I be able to find this location that is clearly marked on Google Map (much harder to find in real life), will a beggar child jab at me today while others stare to see if I would part with any rupees, is my family in danger of Ebola at home, do we have enough change for a snack and a rickshaw ride&hellip;</p>

<p>I love the feeling of being able to walk to many places.  Children play loudly in the yard everyday. They run, and scream, and dance.  Street food are inexpensive yet delicious.  Many seem to be healthy; I rarely ever see a chubby person let alone any obesity.  Women and men love to wear traditional clothes.  Everybody is festive.  Dogs walk around unafraid to be eaten.  There are always beautiful exotic tropical flowers on the streets.  Fruits and vegetables are fresh and full of flavor.</p>

<p>I feel guilty that I don&rsquo;t dare walking through a slum for fearing that I could be harmed in some way.  I do not know Hindi and I don&rsquo;t even attempt to learn any.  I am guilty for being disappointing when a person here does not speak English (which is most of them). I neglect washing the dishes some day because I know housekeeping will do it. I would not give money to beggars but eat expensive meal sometimes.</p>

<p>I hate to always have my backpack checked and tied up (so I couldn&rsquo;t steal anything) when entering a mall, a bank, a convenient store, a grocery store&hellip;  The Internet is too slow and unsteady.  Not many people smile, nobody hugs.  Some locals feel just to charge me more because I&rsquo;m a foreigner.  Any paper works is a nightmare.  Some people appear to be malnourished and overworked.  Beef, pork, and tofu are hard to find, almost non-existent.  Garlics are tiny (very painful to peel).</p>

<p>But all in all, the goods are really good and the bads are really not that bad.  And learning to embrace cultural and life-style differences are challenges I gladly accept as many times as I&rsquo;m given the chance.</p>

<p>I will love you India - in time!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things Are in Motion]]></title>
    <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/09/10/things-are-in-motion/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-10T11:31:50+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/09/10/things-are-in-motion</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After what seemed to be forever, Adam finally got his visa last week and now is on his twenty-hours flight to Mumbai.  His company will send a person with a sign that says &ldquo;Mr. Russell&rdquo; at the airport and take him to his apartment in Pune.  I was relieved to know that he will not have to try to find a cab at 4 in the morning.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello Again]]></title>
    <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/08/23/hello-again/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-23T01:03:20+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/08/23/hello-again</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been too long since I last had a blog. Typing these first few lines seems rather silly and unfamiliar.</p>

<p>This summer has been a mixture of suspense, rush, and leisure.</p>

<p>Adam is still waiting patiently for his <a href="http://www.in.ckgs.us/visa/type-of-visa/employment-visa.shtml">employment visa</a> from the Indian Consulate in Houston. Since May 21, 2014, <a href="http://www.in.ckgs.us/index.shtml">Cox &amp; Kings Global Service</a> (CKGS) is the only authorized Service Provider for the Embassy of India and its Consulates across the USA for Indian Visa. The process has been more than painful.  All the paper works must first go through CKGS before they send it to the Indian Consulate.  Forget competency, forget sanity, forget reason.  Don&rsquo;t be surprise if they still ask for a tax form (which was not listed in the required documents) after you already re-submitted the dang form three times previously.  Seven weeks have passed since Adam first submitted the lengthy paper works.  Still nothing.  Imagine of having to deal directly with pure bureaucrats once on Indian soil!  Should I start &ldquo;praying&rdquo; for our survival?</p>

<p>As much as I am excited to experience India, I am starting to get wary about this trip.  I cannot even apply for my <a href="http://www.in.ckgs.us/visa/type-of-visa/entry-visa.shtml">entry visa</a> until Adam get his.  Who knows how much longer they will drag it out since I was not born here (naturalized citizen takes longer to be processed than American-born).  There is a chance that Adam will be finished with his 6-month assignment and I am still visa-less.  Hah!</p>

<p>Oh well, at least I am still alive and well for another day.  Just a weekend with coconut chicken waffle and yummy beer, and all the blues will be away.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
