<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Visa | Scribbles]]></title>
  <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/categories/visa/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-21T19:08:03+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://thienscribbles.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Thien Truong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to India, Mr. Truong]]></title>
    <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/09/19/welcome-to-india/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-19T08:37:35+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/09/19/welcome-to-india</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I crossed all the phalanges I have and my wish came true.  My visa came back 10 days after I sent it in.  Even better, I applied for the 6 months entry visa and they granted my stay until Adam&rsquo;s visa expires - August 28, 2015.  However, each of my stay cannot exceed 180 days, which will not be a problem since I&rsquo;ll come home for Christmas.</p>

<p>Two days later, after some speedy packing, house cleaning, and last minute errand running, I said goodbye to home and headed to Mumbai.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Mr. Truong&rdquo; - the sign read when the hotel&rsquo;s cab driver greeted me at Chhatrapati Shivaji International Airport (BOM) last night.  Well, Mr. Truong was all chatty until &ldquo;he&rdquo; realized that the driver did not talk much at all.  He did not smile, mostly just pointed me to the direction needed.  I was not helping the situation when I absolutely forgot to tip him.</p>

<p>Tipping is such a tricky business when traveling to a new country.  When should I tip?  How much is appropriate?  I should have read up on it before I left, but oh well.  Plenty of chances to practice now that I&rsquo;m gonna be here for the next 6 months or so.</p>

<p>The drive from BOM to the hotel was short, about 15 mintues.  The streets were still very active at 9:30 p.m.  Men gathered into countless small groups at all the tiny shops and shags.  Many wandered nonchalantly on the streets.  From what I&rsquo;ve seen, Mumbai seems old and run down - many slums.  The streets are narrow and somewhat dark.  Most of the lights were from street vendors.</p>

<p>The quiet driver dropped me off at Hotel Kohinoor Continental.  Dinner buffet and breakfast were complimentary.  Since I just had &ldquo;breakfast&rdquo; on the plane, I settled for some water over dinner.  My room was on the 5th floor over looking the streets below.  I stayed up until four in the morning doing homework just to find out that I could not upload my assignement due to the hotel&rsquo;s excruciatingly slow Internet.  After a shower with some very powerful scented shampoo and bar soap, I force myself to nap for a few hours so that I can wake up in time for breakfast not feeling like a cranky zombie.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things Are in Motion]]></title>
    <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/09/10/things-are-in-motion/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-10T11:31:50+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/09/10/things-are-in-motion</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After what seemed to be forever, Adam finally got his visa last week and now is on his twenty-hours flight to Mumbai.  His company will send a person with a sign that says &ldquo;Mr. Russell&rdquo; at the airport and take him to his apartment in Pune.  I was relieved to know that he will not have to try to find a cab at 4 in the morning.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello Again]]></title>
    <link href="http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/08/23/hello-again/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-23T01:03:20+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://thienscribbles.com/blog/2014/08/23/hello-again</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been too long since I last had a blog. Typing these first few lines seems rather silly and unfamiliar.</p>

<p>This summer has been a mixture of suspense, rush, and leisure.</p>

<p>Adam is still waiting patiently for his <a href="http://www.in.ckgs.us/visa/type-of-visa/employment-visa.shtml">employment visa</a> from the Indian Consulate in Houston. Since May 21, 2014, <a href="http://www.in.ckgs.us/index.shtml">Cox &amp; Kings Global Service</a> (CKGS) is the only authorized Service Provider for the Embassy of India and its Consulates across the USA for Indian Visa. The process has been more than painful.  All the paper works must first go through CKGS before they send it to the Indian Consulate.  Forget competency, forget sanity, forget reason.  Don&rsquo;t be surprise if they still ask for a tax form (which was not listed in the required documents) after you already re-submitted the dang form three times previously.  Seven weeks have passed since Adam first submitted the lengthy paper works.  Still nothing.  Imagine of having to deal directly with pure bureaucrats once on Indian soil!  Should I start &ldquo;praying&rdquo; for our survival?</p>

<p>As much as I am excited to experience India, I am starting to get wary about this trip.  I cannot even apply for my <a href="http://www.in.ckgs.us/visa/type-of-visa/entry-visa.shtml">entry visa</a> until Adam get his.  Who knows how much longer they will drag it out since I was not born here (naturalized citizen takes longer to be processed than American-born).  There is a chance that Adam will be finished with his 6-month assignment and I am still visa-less.  Hah!</p>

<p>Oh well, at least I am still alive and well for another day.  Just a weekend with coconut chicken waffle and yummy beer, and all the blues will be away.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
